A Guide to the Governor Thomas Mann Randolph Executive Papers, 1819-1822
Library of Virginia
Additional significant correspondence includes the following: J. G. Jackson resigning as brigadier general (1820 Jan. 1); applications for the office of Clerk of the Council (1820 Jan.); John P. Shields re. the completion of his contract to plant trees on the Public Square (1820 Jan. 19); applications for assistant clerk or copying clerk of the Council (1820 Jan.); Thomas M. Randolph, President of the Literary Fund, encl. the report of the state of the Literary Fund (1820 Feb. 14); John P. Shields re. his claim for work done on Capitol Square (1820 May 1); Robert Stanard, Attorney of the U. S. for the Virginia District, requesting that a convict be received at the Penitentiary (1820 May 26); John Hills, 1st Lieutenant of Ordnance, re. the evacuation of the General Government from Ft. Powhatan and the removal of all property belonging to the United States (1820 July 13); John C. Montague re. his proposal to graduate the graveling part of the Public Square forming a horseshoe (1820 Oct. 17); Robert Watkins & John T. Ayres proposing to complete the Capitol Square by graveling, turfing, planting, & replanting trees (1820 Oct. 19); Philip P. Barbour re. compensation as counsel for Virginia in the U. S. Supreme Court (1820 Nov. 25); William Munford, William McKim, & Robert Greenhow, Directors of the Penitentiary, submitting a statement of the operations of the Penitentiary (1820 Nov. 30); John W. Taylor re. the death of William A. Burwell (1821 Feb. 22); Peter Randolph resigning as judge of the General Court (1821 Feb. 22); recommendations & applications for Clerk of the Council in place of John Burfoot (1821 Feb. & March); applications for the office of adjutant general (1821 March); applications for the office of military lands in Kentucky (1821 March 23); Samuel Taylor declining an appointment as judge of the General Court (1821 March 28); Thomas T. Bouldin accepting an appointment as judge of the General Court (1821 March 30); J. W. Pleasants, Assistant Clerk of the Council, re. pay for performing the duties as Clerk of the Council & Assistant Clerk for sixteen days (1821 March 31); Lt. E. Brown, Public Guard, re. receipts for the pay & supplies for the guard stationed at Ft. Powhatan (1821 April 19); C. Tompkins re. an estimate of the repairs of the Magazine at Westham (1821 May 26); John Dupignac re. permission to raise a balloon on Capitol Square (1821 Aug. 21); Richard Eppes suggesting a portion of the Public Guard at the Manufactory of Arms for the protection of public property until its operations cease on 1 January 1822 (1821 Dec. 15); William W. Hening requesting access to the archives of the Council Chamber to research the situation of unsatisfied claims for land bounties of the troops engaged on state establishment during the Revolution (1822 Jan. 22); James Warrell asking for permission to lay logs to draw off the water continually escaping from the spring in the northeast part of Capitol Square which leaves the Museum in a damp & humid state (1822 Jan. 22); Robert B. Taylor accepting a commission as major general of the 4th Division of Militia (1822 Jan. 28); John S. Hening re. compensation for his services as agent for the claimants of military lands lying west of the Tennessee River in Kentucky (1822 Feb. 18); John Adams, Mayor of Richmond, re. the division of the city into wards (1822 March 11); John Adams complaining of the Keeper of the Locks of the James River Canal (1822 May 20); Lt. Col. Bomford, U. S. Ordnance Dept., re. the delivery of arms to the Virginia Militia according to the act of Congress for arming the militia of the United States (1822 June 22); E. Brown encl. the sale at auction of the house & other property found at Ft. Powhatan (1822 June 28); Daniel Morgan re. the death of Thomas Van Swearingen, a representative in Congress (1822 Sept. 2); John W. Green accepting his appointment as judge of the Court of Appeals (1822 Oct. 11); Peyton Drew, Clerk of the General Court, re. repairs to his office in the Capitol (1822 Oct. 11); Philip P. Barbour declining an appointment as chancellor (1822 Oct. 13); and William G. Pendleton, Register of the Land Office, encl. an estimate of certain repairs needed for the Land Office (1822 Oct. 23).
Other noteworthy items include: certificates of oath for Thomas Mann Randolph as governor (1819 Dec. 13 & 1821 Dec. 15), Jerman Baker as Treasurer (1820 Jan. 29), William Smith as a member of the Privy Council (1820 Feb. 23), & William H. Richardson as clerk of the Privy Council (1821 March 7); proclamations of Governor Randolph & Lt. Governor Peter V. Daniel offering a reward for the apprehension of escaped convicts (1820 Jan. 5 & 15; 1820 June 13 & 19; 1820 July 20; 1820 Oct. 24; 1820 Nov. 18; 1820 Dec. 19; 1821 March 23; 1821 April 16; 1821 Aug. 16 & 25; 1821 Nov. 5 & 26; 1821 Dec. 15; 1822 Feb. 12; 1822 April 12; 1822 June 28; 1822 July 6; & 1822 Sept. 7 & 20); proceedings of the Board of Directors of the Penitentiary (1820 March 4; 1820 April 8; 1820 June 10, 17, & 24; 1820 Aug. 12 & 19; 1820 Oct. 7 & 28; 1820 Dec. 9, 16, & 30; 1821 Feb. 9 & 17; 1821 March 14 & 30; 1821 May 23; 1821 June 13 & 20; 1821 July 5 & 18; 1821 Sept. 26; 1821 Nov. 2; 1821 Dec. 12; 1822 Jan. 23 & 30; 1822 Feb. 13, 19, & 27; 1822 March 8 & 27; 1822 April 17; 1822 May 1 & 29; 1822 July 17; 1822 Aug. 7; & 1822 Oct. 26); proclamation of Governor Randolph re. the compact between the Commonwealth & James River Company (1820 March 16); report of the Committee for examining the Capitol Square (1820 April 21); reports of the Committee to examine the Auditor & Treasurer's Offices (1820 May 9; 1820 Dec.5; 1821 April 25; 1821 July 25; 1821 Nov. 20; 1822 March 9; & 1822 Nov. 18); a proclamation of Lt. Gov Peter V. Daniel re. an election to fill the vacancy in Congress occasioned by the resignation of James Pindall (1820 Aug. 5); proclamation of Governor Randolph re. indemnification for the loss of slaves carried away by British officers after the conclusion of peace (1821 April 18); proclamation of Governor Randolph re. the rates of pilotage for foreign vessels (1821 July 10); report of the Committee to whom was referred the reports & resolutions of the legislatures of Maryland & New Hampshire and the proceeding in the U. S. Senate re. appropriations of public lands for the purpose of education (1821 Dec. [N.D.]); report of the Committee appointed to divide the City of Richmond into wards (1822 March 22); contract between Lewis Ludlam & Bernard Peyton to remove all ordnance, etc., from Ft. Powhatan to the Armory in Richmond (1822 April 17); bond of Arthur S. Brockenbrough, Proctor, & Thomas Jefferson, Rector, to renew certificate No. 32 in favor of the Proctor of Central College as Proctor of the University of Virginia (1822 July 6); proclamation of Governor Randolph re. an election to fill the vacancy in the House of Representatives by the death of Thomas Van Swearingen (1822 Sept. 7); proclamation of Governor Randolph appointing Philip P. Barbour as judge of the High Court of Chancery to replace John W. Green (1822 Oct. 11); resolutions of Kentucky providing for the appointment of a Board of Commissioners under the 8th article of the compact with Virginia & ratifying the Convention of the commissioners appointed to make the necessary arrangements for constituting the Board (1822 Nov. 22); and the contract of Herman Boye to complete the work of John Wood (1822 Nov. 22).
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by date of document with pardons and undated items arranged to the rear.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Flournoy, H. W., CALENDAR OF VIRGINIA STATE PAPERS, January 1, 1808-December 31, 1835, VOL. X, Richmond: James E. Goode, Printer, 1892.
Contents List
- Thomas Mann Randolph Executive Papers
- 1819
  - December
    - 12-20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 21-31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1820
  - January
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 21-31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - February
    - 1-14 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 15-29 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - March
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 16-31 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - April
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 16-29 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - May
    - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - June
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 12-20 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 21-30 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - July
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 21-31 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - August
    - 1-14 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - September
    - 2-29 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - October
    - 2-20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 21-31 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - November
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 17-30 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - December
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 16-31 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 1821
  - January
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 16-31 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - February
    - 4-22 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 23-28 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - March
    - 1-6 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 7-14 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 15-31 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - April
    - 2-20 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 21-30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - May
    - 1-26 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 27-31 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - June
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 11-20 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 21-25 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 26-30 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - July
    - 2-10 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 12-20 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 21-31 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - August (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - September (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - October (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - November (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - December
    - 1-11 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 12-31 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Pardons
    - A-P (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - R-W (Box 5, Folder 8)
- 1821
  - January
    - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 16-30 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - February
    - 1-16 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 17-28 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - March
    - 2-20 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 22-29 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - April
    - 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 16-30 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - May
    - 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 16-25 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 26-31 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - June
    - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 11-17 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 18-22 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - 24-30 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - July
    - 1-15 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 16-31 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - August
    - 2-20 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 23-31 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - September (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - October
    - 1-15 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 16-31 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - November
    - 1-18 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - 19-30 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - December (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Pardons (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Oversized (Clamshell Box)
  - 1819
    - Dec. 14 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1820
    - Jan. 4 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Jan. 7 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Feb. 9 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Feb. 14 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - March 15 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - April 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - May 6 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - June 1 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - July 10 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 1821
    - April 20 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - April 24 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - June 7 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - June 19 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - June 25 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - June 26 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - June 28 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - July 4 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - July 25 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Aug. 14 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Aug. 30 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Oct. 4 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Oct. 27 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Oct. 29 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Nov. 27 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Dec. 22 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - 1822
    - June 18 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - June 29 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Nov. 1 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Nov. 16 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Nov. 22 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Dec. 11 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Oversized (Newspaper Box)
  - 1819
    - Dec. 15 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1820
    - March 23 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - June 8 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Oct. 9 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Oct. 29 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Nov. 30 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Nov. 30 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1821
    - Jan. 8 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Feb. 17 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - May 21 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Nov. 27 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Dec. 11 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Dec. 21 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Dec. 31 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - 1822
    - Nov. 6 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Nov. 6 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Dec. 2 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Dec. 10 (Box 10, Folder 18)